<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Home on Shen Ting Ang</title><link>https://shenting.org/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Shen Ting Ang</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.6</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shenting.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Another Move</title><link>https://shenting.org/post/welcome/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shenting.org/post/welcome/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to switch back to Github Pages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Great Gatsby: 100 Years Later</title><link>https://shenting.org/post/thegreatgatsby/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shenting.org/post/thegreatgatsby/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-death-of-the-american-dream">The Death of the American Dream&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I recall watching the movie adaptation of The Great Gatsby back in 2013. Baz Luhrmann created a visual spectacle, featuring Leonardo DiCaprio as the titular character who has become part of multiple memes. And who can forget Lana Del Rey&amp;rsquo;s haunting vocals for the theme &amp;ldquo;Young and Beautiful&amp;rdquo;? I read the original novel soon after, and was pretty struck by how deep the underlying themes run.
Fast forward to 2025, and it has been exactly a century since F. Scott Fitzgerald published The Great Gatsby. One hundred years later, its themes feel eerily familiar. The excessive wealth, the disillusionment, the relentless pursuit of a dream—all of it maps almost perfectly onto today’s tech-fueled, crypto-charged, influencer-driven landscape. This struck me on a commute home last week and as I thought about it, the main characters do reflect segments of modern day society.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DataScience SG Talk: Data Challenges</title><link>https://shenting.org/post/datachallenges/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shenting.org/post/datachallenges/</guid><description>&lt;p>I gave a talk last night at Data Science SG entitled “Trustable Data: Challenges in a National Sports Association”. It gives an outline of what I’ve encountered and done in the past few years for SCBA. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1h88SZ2S25xFc9JAjCdBfWVK-edYJj_btPIN5gI2Za-A/edit">Talk slides can be found here&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why you probably shouldn't outsource data work</title><link>https://shenting.org/post/outsource_data_work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shenting.org/post/outsource_data_work/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was having a conversation with David and the subject of outsourcing came up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll start by stating I am not against outsourcing. There are definitely situations where it makes sense, especially for resource-constrained organizations who can’t possibly cover every single function by themselves. (On a personal level, hosting this site on SquareSpace is also a form of outsourcing.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Outsourcing does work for one-off projects where it doesn’t make sense for an organization to hire long-term. So, if you’re working on a one-off data project, it probably makes sense to outsource the work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mandatory Reading on Names</title><link>https://shenting.org/post/names/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shenting.org/post/names/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.kalzumeus.com/2010/06/17/falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-names/">Yes, we’re talking about actual names&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a pity that I came across this 6 months too late, as it would have saved me an hour repeating myself thrice on why we can’t use names as a unique key to join across different data sources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thankfully my point eventually got across, but to any fellow developer/data scientist/engineer having to explain to stakeholders, hopefully this helps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And no, you do not want to use email addresses as a unique key either:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rating Systems (2): Glicko-2</title><link>https://shenting.org/post/rating_2_glicko/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shenting.org/post/rating_2_glicko/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="point-vs-interval-estimates">Point vs Interval Estimates&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>One issue with the Elo system as previously raised is how it doesn’t give any information about the uncertainty of the estimate. The Glicko system is an attempt to encompass this information additionally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Think about this: If a player has played 3 games: win against a player rated 1500, lose against a player rated 1450 and win against a player rated 1200, how confident are we in the derived rating? On the other hand, if a player has played 50 games, and has won 35 games against opponents rated 2000 and below, drew 5 games against opponents rated 2000-2050 and lost the remaining 10 games versus opponents rated above 2050, we can be fairly certain that his rating is somewhere between 2000-2050.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RPA Career Talk</title><link>https://shenting.org/post/rpa_career_talk/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shenting.org/post/rpa_career_talk/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was invited by the Rafflesian Parents Association to give a talk on being a data scientist (as part of a five speaker panel) earlier today. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1yVgou8qDtAnGLuzDmCcoxjOIzAi48JJdgtd5MWqeruk/edit?usp=sharing">Here are the slides.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Was not totally happy as I didn’t realise that Google Sheets speaker notes covers the actual slides when I was screen sharing over zoom. Also, this is the first time I’ve actually given a career talk, and realised it was 15 years ago when I was sitting in the audience on the other side. Time flies!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rating Systems (1): Elo and its limitations</title><link>https://shenting.org/post/rating_1_elo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shenting.org/post/rating_1_elo/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>This is going to be a new series on rating systems, which is a vastly underrated (pun intended) area of statistics and data science. Rating systems has actually been a part of my life (and probably yours), from early days in chess and then games with matchmaking like CS:GO and Valorant, to now thinking if contract bridge should also have one.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="historical-context">Historical Context&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Having been around for centuries, chess is a game which people have wasted much time on arguing/debating who is the best player. It’s probably slightly surprising then that the first modern rating systems only appeared around or after the end of World War 2. The first systems (Ingo and Harkness) were quite simple and used the idea of the average rating of opponents with adjustments for the results.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DataScience SG Talk on Sample Count and Podcast</title><link>https://shenting.org/post/podcast_dssg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shenting.org/post/podcast_dssg/</guid><description>&lt;p>A while ago, I wrote about the &lt;a href="sample_count_2">GE2020 sample count&lt;/a>. Together with Yong Sheng,[] we gave a talk about this at DataScience SG last night (Youtube link)](&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U9-zax0mMrw)">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U9-zax0mMrw)&lt;/a>. Do also check out the second talk as reinforcement learning is always an interesting subject - props to Siddarth for giving that quick summary of RL!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://anchor.fm/symbolic-connection/episodes/015--Ang-Shen-Ting--Data-Scientist-with-INSEAD-ejep1e/a-a1pvsb">Also, Symbolic Connection’s episode featuring me is now live!&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to Koo Ping Shung for organizing both of the above.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Much Should You Trust the Sample Count?</title><link>https://shenting.org/post/sample_count_1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shenting.org/post/sample_count_1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Election season is upon us again here in Singapore and Polling Day is this Friday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The last election in 2015 introduced the sample count. What is the sample count? &lt;a href="https://www.eld.gov.sg/mediarelease/SampleCount_Generic.pdf">From the ELD Website&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the votes cast at each polling station, a counting assistant picks up a random bundle of 100 ballot papers (in front of the candidates and counting agents present) and counts the number of votes for each candidate (or group of candidates in the case of a GRC).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Much Should You Trust the Sample Count?</title><link>https://shenting.org/post/sample_count_2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shenting.org/post/sample_count_2/</guid><description>&lt;p>(Note: This was originally posted on Facebook)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TL;DR While the sample counts of this year’s GE saw some huge deviations, they are mostly within expectation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The two hour extension brought about some online groans from friends who didn’t want to stay up late to follow the results. To help alleviate some of this anxiety, &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/198pBnso8oFpNSB2vNOSi-Cv5ZtIZl7lPvdk0_syZd6M/">I decided to set up a tracking sheet for the sample counts with estimated win probabilities to let people decide if the final count was worth waiting for.&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>