<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Data Science on Shen Ting Ang</title><link>https://shenting.org/tags/data-science/</link><description>Recent content in Data Science on Shen Ting Ang</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.6</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shenting.org/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DataScience SG Talk: Data Challenges</title><link>https://shenting.org/post/datachallenges/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shenting.org/post/datachallenges/</guid><description>&lt;p>I gave a talk last night at Data Science SG entitled “Trustable Data: Challenges in a National Sports Association”. It gives an outline of what I’ve encountered and done in the past few years for SCBA. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1h88SZ2S25xFc9JAjCdBfWVK-edYJj_btPIN5gI2Za-A/edit">Talk slides can be found here&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why you probably shouldn't outsource data work</title><link>https://shenting.org/post/outsource_data_work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shenting.org/post/outsource_data_work/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was having a conversation with David and the subject of outsourcing came up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll start by stating I am not against outsourcing. There are definitely situations where it makes sense, especially for resource-constrained organizations who can’t possibly cover every single function by themselves. (On a personal level, hosting this site on SquareSpace is also a form of outsourcing.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Outsourcing does work for one-off projects where it doesn’t make sense for an organization to hire long-term. So, if you’re working on a one-off data project, it probably makes sense to outsource the work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mandatory Reading on Names</title><link>https://shenting.org/post/names/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shenting.org/post/names/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.kalzumeus.com/2010/06/17/falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-names/">Yes, we’re talking about actual names&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a pity that I came across this 6 months too late, as it would have saved me an hour repeating myself thrice on why we can’t use names as a unique key to join across different data sources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thankfully my point eventually got across, but to any fellow developer/data scientist/engineer having to explain to stakeholders, hopefully this helps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And no, you do not want to use email addresses as a unique key either:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>